Finding Aid for Wystan Stevens Papers, 1961-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Wystan Stevens papers 1961-1973
Stevens, Wystan.
1 oversize folders
1.5 linear feet
86108 Aa 2; UAm
Ann Arbor, Michigan, local historian; collector of leaflets and photographs on local history topics.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Wystan Stevens (donor no. 4452 ) over a period of years.
The collection is open to research.
Ann Arbor, Michigan, local historian. Wystan Stevens at one time was a staff member of the Michigan Historical Collections. Part of his responsibility was to locate and collect materials distributed by student groups on campus.
The collection consists of leaflets, newsletters, and other miscellanea relating to activist organizations and events in Ann Arbor and at the University of Michigan during the period of the mid-1960s to the early 1970s. Other materials were added to the collection by staff members of the Michigan Historical Collections, 1969-1973. The collection, arranged alphabetically, provides an overview of the activities, personalities, and political debates of the time. Included is a small series of historical Ann Arbor photographs, either originals or photoprints of originals, collected from different sources.
Subjects:
African American newspapers--Michigan--Bibliography.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Ann Arbor Foundry Company.; Radicalism--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor High School (Mich.). Class of 1910.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Butchers.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Fires--1899.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Bethlehem Evangelical Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Bollinger House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Butchers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Celebrations.; Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Concordia College (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Dexter (Mich.); Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Earhart House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Eschelbach's Meat Market (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Fifth Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Fires--Michigan--Ann Arbor--1899.; First German Methodist Episcopal Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); German Americans--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Haarer Building (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Henry House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Holidays.; Huron Hills Golf Club (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Interiors.; Labor Day.; Law Quadrangle (University of Michigan); Liberty Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Mack & Company (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Mack's Garage (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Main Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Parades and processions--1911-1921.; Reorganized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Roy House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Scio (Mich.: Township)--Churches.; Second Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Sherick House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Sixth Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); University of Michigan--Commencements--1921-1930.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1921-1930.; Veteran's Day.; Voght House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Walker Building (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Washington Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Washtenaw Country Club.; Washtenaw County (Mich.). Board of Supervisors.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Organizations.; World War, 1914-1918.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organizations and Events File
  - ADC Mothers Protest 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Alpha Omega Fellowship 1969 (Box 1)
  - America in Crisis Teach-in 1967 (Box 1)
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - American Friends Service Committee undated (Box 1)
  - American Revolutionary Media 1970 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Black Theatre 1969 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Film Festival 1963-1968 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Free School 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Politics 1965, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Politics 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor School Board Elections 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor United Fund 1968 (Box 1)
  - Association for Commitment to World Responsibility 1962 (Box 1)
  - Bach Club 1969 (Box 1)
  - Biafra Relief 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Black Action Movement Strike 1970 (Box 1)
  - Black Berets 1969 (Box 1)
  - Black Student Union 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Boulding Write-In Campaign for Congress 1966 (Box 1)
  - Campus Action 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Children's Community School 1966, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Cinema Guild (Box 1)
  - Cinema II (Box 1)
  - Citizens for a National Primary 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Citizens for Educational Freedom 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Citizens for New Politics (New Politics Party) 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - College Republicans 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - Committee of Responsibility of Ann Arbor (Box 1)
  - Committee on Soviet Jewry 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Community Food-Co-op (Box 1)
  - Concerned Citizens of Ann Arbor 1969 (Box 1)
  - Congress of Racial Equality 1964 (Box 1)
  - Council on Adoptable Children (Box 1)
  - Draft Board sit-in 1965 (Box 1)
  - Drug Teach-in 1968 (Box 1)
  - Emergency Conference on China 1966 (Box 1)
  - English Department 1969 (Box 1)
  - Forum (School of Social Work) (Box 1)
  - Free University 1966 (Box 1)
  - Gay Liberation 1970 (Box 1)
  - Grape Boycott (Box 1)
  - Humphrey for President Committee 1968 (Box 1)
  - Independent Socialist Club 1969 (Box 1)
  - Inter-Cooperative Council 1968 (Box 1)
  - Interfaith Council for Peace 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Inter House Assembly 1966 (Box 1)
  - Inter Quadrangle Council 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Logos Bookstore 1969 (Box 1)
  - Martin Luther King Memorial Fund 1968 (Box 1)
  - Marxist Discussion Group 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Mobilization Committee 1969 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Petition Drive for Peace (Box 1)
  - Movie Price Hike Protest 1965 (Box 1)
  - New Politics Party 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - New Democratic Coalition 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Organization of Arab Students 1969 (Box 1)
  - People Against Racism (Box 1)
  - Psychologists for Action and Social Responsibility 1968 (Box 1)
  - Radical Caucus 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Radical Education Project, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Rent Strike (Tenants Union) 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Resistance 1966-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ross Barnett speech 1963 (Box 1)
  - St. Andrews Church Social Action Committee 1968, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Society for the Emancipation of the American Male 1969 (Box 1)
  - Society of Classical Liberalism 1968 (Box 1)
  - Student Counseling Office 1969 (Box 1)
  - Student Credit Union 1969 (Box 1)
  - Student Economic Union 1966 (Box 1)
  - Student Food Cooperatives, Boycotts, etc. 1969 (Box 1)
  - Student Government Council (Box 1)
  - Student Peace Union 1966 (Box 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (Voice) 1963-1968, 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (Jesse James Gang) 1968-1970 (Box 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (Eastern Michigan University) (Box 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (Michigan State University) 1968 (Box 1)
  - Students for Educational Information 1969 (Box 1)
  - Students for McCarthy 1968 (Box 1)
  - Tutorial and Cultural Relations Project 1966 (Box 1)
  - University Activities Committee 1968 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Friends of SNCC 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Vietnam Teach-in 1965 (Box 1)
  - Vietnam War, opposition to (Box 1)
  - Voter's Pledge Campaign on Vietnam 1966 (Box 1)
  - White Panthers, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom 1969 (Box 2)
  - Young Americans for Freedom 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Young Democrats 1967-1968 (Box 2)
  - Young Socialist Alliance 1966 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous flyers 1969-1971, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, various, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - 1037 Jones Drive, Ann Arbor (Box 2)
    (information on building once used as brewery)
  - Checklist and survey notes of African American newspapers in Michigan 1969 (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Armistice Day 1918 (Box 2)
  - Eschelbach's Meat Market 1904 (Box 2)
  - Haarer and Walker Buildings 1973 (Box 2)
  - Homes used in Old West Side Home Tour Brochure 1973 (Box 2)
  - Huron Hills Golf Club directors 1934 and Ann Arbor High School Junior party, 1909 (Box 2)
  - Labor Day 1916 (Box 2)
  - Mack & Co. fire 1899 Main Street businesses; other buildings (Box 2)
  - Photo album of an unknown University of Michigan law student circa 1924 (Box 2)
  - Portraits, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous oversize, 1 folders
    - Mack & Co. photos (Folder UAm)
    - Zion Church 1881 (Folder UAm)
      (later called Bethlehem Church; not Zion Lutheran Church)
    - Washtenaw County Board of Supervisors (Folder UAm)
    - Dexter portrait composite (Folder UAm)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder UAm)